You always outrun me,
虽然每次都被你追过去
but not today.
但是今天你别想追上我
Keep it steady.
要撑住…
I must run faster.
我要追上
She overtook her from the flank with a tiny margin.
以些微之差从外侧超越了
Arima... Arima...
有马…
Let's win Arima Kinen.
夺下有马…
Kitasan, are you...
北部 这次又怎么了…
3 G1 WINS
(GI三胜)
0 G1 WIN
(GI零胜)
Miss Nature...
优秀素质老师…
Help me, please.
请你救救我…
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
"SHIRUKO" You can have it.
(汁粉) 拿去吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
"EPISODE 8: SOMETHING IRREPLACEABLE" What's bothering you this time?
(第8话 一直存在之物) 所以 这次又是怎么了呢
It's... about Diamond.
那个…是光钻的事
Oh? Did you two argue?
怎么了 你们吵架了吗
Not really.
倒也不是这样
She totally crushed me in Arima Kinen.
我在有马纪念 彻底输给她了
Crushed?
彻底
Did she?
有吗
You only lost to her by a tiny margin.
不是只输她一点点吗
It was a thrilling race.
那是场很棒的比赛啊
Look.
你看
"NAILBITER! SATONO DIAMOND VS KITASAN BLACK" It's on the news too.
(大激战 里见光钻对北部玄驹) 新闻报道也都写出来了
You can have ten rematches
就算再比十次 结果也是各有千秋 你们的实力就是如此相近
We all think you two are equals,
大家都这么说
including me.
我也是这样想的
Why?
你是怎么了
Have you lost your confidence like you did last year?
难道说又像去年一样 失去自信了吗
No, it's not that.
不是这样的
I'm still confident in myself.
与其说是我失去自信
It's just that Diamond is...
不如说是光钻她…
Diamond is simply too amazing.
光钻她…太强了
Before the race, she gave out this vibe that intimidated me.
在开赛前她身上的氛围 就给我一种浑身刺痛的感觉
Intimidate?
浑身刺痛
During the race, I was so anxious.
在比赛时也让我战栗不己
I was only slightly behind her, but the gap
明明只落后一点点 却完全不觉得追得上去
felt insurmountable.
感觉那么地遥远
Come on!
没事啦
You are pretty good yourself!
你也很强啊
At least that's what I think.
至少我是这么想的
Nature...
素质…
Drink this now.
先把那个喝了
It'll lift your spirit.
打起精神来吧
It's sweet and delicious.
甜甜的很好喝哦
Right.
是啊
Thank you, Miss Nature.
谢谢你 老师
Miss Nature again...
老师…
N—Nothing.
没事 没什么
SHIRUKO
(汁粉)
KAMO SHRINE
(加茂神社)
It's crowded today.
真是热闹呢
Yeah…
嗯…
What should we do? Do we pray first?
要做什么好呢 要先去参拜吗
Kita?
小北
What's the matter?
你怎么了
I'm fine.
没有 没事
Are you sure?
真的吗
-Come take a look! -Yes.
-来看看哦 -真的…
Oh?
是吗
Have some amazake.
要不要来杯甜酒呢
Try our amazake.
来杯甜酒吧
-It's delicious and will warm your soul. -Look, Diamond. Amazake!
-可以暖暖身子 很好喝哦 -光钻你看 有甜酒耶
-Best amazake in town! -Let's get some.
-我们这摊是最好喝的 -我们去买吧
-It's sweet. -Hi, can I have some amazake?
-很甜哦 -不好意思 我要买甜酒
Welcome.
欢迎光临
1,000 yen, please.
一共1000圆
Our charms
每种护身符都很有用哦
"SURE-WIN CHARM" will not let you down.
(必胜护符)
All right.
好
Can I have this one, please?
我要买这个
Sure, I've received the exact amount.
好的 收你刚好
Kita.
小北
Which charm did you get?
今年你买哪一种护身符呢
Uhm... A sure-win charm.
那个…是胜利护符
Oh?
真的吗
Me too. We match.
我们是一对呢 好开心
Right.
是…是啊
Diamond.
那个…光钻
What wish did you make?
你今年许了什么愿呢
Why do you ask?
怎么这么问呢
You were all serious when you prayed just now.
那个…感觉你在参拜时特别认真
I made a wish to win more races.
我…我的心愿是希望能赢下更多比赛
I made a wish to win Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe.
希望能赢下凯旋门赏
Crown won the G1 in Hong Kong.
皇冠不是赢下了香港的GI吗
She inspired me to step onto the international stage.
看到这样的她 让我也想要向世界挑战
That's why you want to win Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe?
所以才会想要赢下凯旋门赏吗
Mhm.
对
No Japanese horse girls have ever won that.
至今还没有日本赛马娘赢过吧
Some entered the race with full confidence but came out disheartened and quit.
甚至还有满心期待却挑战失败 表示再也赢不了的人在
That's why winning
所以我认为
Prix de l'Arc de Triomphe is very important to me.
现在在那个舞台上获胜 对我而言有非常重大的意义
I want to leave a lasting legacy as a member of the Satono Group.
我想要以里见集团的一员留下成绩
I want to pave the way for the future of Japanese horse girls.
想要对开创日本赛马娘界的未来 贡献一份心力
They are so alike...
她们好像…
Kita, will you come with me?
小北 你也跟我一起去吧
We can race in France together.
一起去法国比赛吧
Me?
我也去吗
Yes.
是啊
Well...
那…那个
I hope to see you there, Kita.
我希望小北也能在那个舞台上
Let's represent Japan
我们一起代表日本
and race against other horse girls.
向全世界的赛马娘挑战吧
Let's see the world beyond our nation.
一起去见识更宽广的世界吧
Okay…
好…
I see it now.
我懂了
Diamond
光钻她…
and Dura are so alike.
跟小鸣很像呢
You have to be patient.
不能急
Verxina.
是姐姐啊
It's too easy to predict where the ball will fall.
落点太容易看穿了
Let's swap.
交换投手
Done.
好
Why are you here?
你来这里干嘛
No reason.
没干嘛
I don't need your encouragement.
我不需要被人鼓励
You are as stubborn as always.
你还是一样难搞呢
I was planning to buy you a new pair of shoes.
我本来还想给你买双新鞋呢
No, thanks.
不用了
Geez.
真是的
Just let us help you for once.
偶尔也老实地向我们撒娇吧
I'm not like you
我和强击不同
or Vivlos.
跟姐姐也不一样…
No, you're very much like us.
我们很像的
We struggle a lot.
像是一直赢不了的这个部分
What is it?
找我有什么事
How is your injury?
那个…你的伤势如何了
It hasn't fully healed yet.
现在还没完全复原
I see.
这样啊
But it will eventually.
但是迟早会复原
It must.
一定会恢复的
My duty is to prove to the world that I'm the best horse girl.
我的使命就是证明自己是世界最强
One day, I will climb to the top
有朝一日 一定要以自己的力量
on my own.
称霸这个世界
This injury cannot set me back.
不能因为这种小事停滞不前
You're so inspiring.
你果然很厉害
Inspiring?
厉害
You're always so upfront.
因为小鸣总是如此率直
But of course.
这是当然
This is why I run.
因为这是我奔跑的理由
Right.
嗯 是啊
What about you?
你又在看着什么
Huh?
咦
What makes you run?
你前行的目标是什么
What makes me run...?
目标…
The shiny thing before you that you chase after,
在遥远的前方 发出万丈光芒之物
the one thing you want to achieve,
想要成就之事
the reason to keep you running.
也就是你奔跑的理由
I guess I run to win...?
我奔跑的理由…就是获胜吧
And after that?
获胜之后呢
Huh?
咦
Without a new goal, you will cease to improve.
不得不去追求 不能裹足不前
You must have something
必须成就之事
you want to achieve, no?
你一定有吧
I have never set my sights on the international stage.
我从来没想过要挑战世界
That's what makes Diamond and Dura so inspiring.
光钻和小鸣真的很厉害
What I want to achieve, huh?
想要成就之事吗…
I used to...
我在之前…
aspire to become Teio,
一直想要成为帝皇那个样子
"TOKAI TEIO" and be the star
(东海帝皇) (帝王能超越皇帝吗) 成为能够 让大家绽放笑容的闪亮明星
But it doesn't matter anymore.
但是…已经不重要了
Because I know I can never be like her.
因为我已经明白 这是不可能实想的梦想
Therefore,
所以我决定…
I will run in my own distinct style.
要跑出自我 锻炼出自己的风格
I will win one race after another.
不断获胜 赢下胜利
But
但是…
what I want to achieve,
想要成就的事
what I will give my all to obtain,
赌上一切也想去做的事
I don't have anything
那种像是梦想之类的目标
that I can call my dream.
现在的我 并没有那种东西…
Honey, honey, honey.
蜂蜜…
Once I have a taste of honey...
只要舔了蜂蜜…
Done.
好
Welcome back, Kita.
小北辛苦了
Teio.
帝皇
Hi, Teio.
辛…辛苦了
Well... I...
那个…我…
What's the matter, Kita?
怎么啦 小北
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《赛马娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
One, two, three, four. Two, two, three, four.
一二三四 二二三四…
Teio.
那个 帝皇
Is it your dream to be the undefeated triple crown horse girl?
帝皇的梦想 是成为无败三冠赛马娘对吧
That's right.
是啊
To be precise, I want to be someone as awesome as Rudolf.
准确来说 是成为会长那样的帅气赛马娘才对
Have you watched her race before?
你有看过会长的比赛吗
You'll be starstruck.
很惊人哦
She's stronger,
比任何人都还要强
faster, and brighter than anyone.
比任何人都还要快 还要闪亮
Every day, I tell myself to be someone like her.
我每天都喊着 要成为会长那样的人呢
I want to be the undefeated triple crown horse girl.
心里想着一定要成为 无败三冠赛马娘
But I couldn't do it.
不过最后没能实现就是了
Despite all that,
但是…即便如此
you stuck to your dream?
帝皇你还是坚持了下来对吧
Mhm.
是啊
You keep chasing after your dream.
一直都追寻着某个梦想…
What keeps you going?
为什么你能够这么坚持呢
Well...
这个嘛…
I missed out on the triple crown races due to my injury.
我在因为受伤无缘三冠后
Then, I went to watch Kikuka Sho.
去看了菊花赏的比赛
I was moved.
很震撼
Everyone raced with their dream and pride.
所有人都背负着梦想和骄傲 在奔跑着
They gave their all to win.
拼命想要获得胜利
I think that's awesome.
真的很帅气
It rekindled my spirit.
让我有了勇气
I can't be a triple crown horse girl, but I still want to be undefeated.
就算与三冠无缘 我也要成为不败的赛马娘
I had a lot of doubts and second guesses.
虽然在这之后 还是有很多挫折和迷惘
I even changed my dream.
甚至改变了梦想
Still...
即便如此…
Someone gave me a goal to strive toward.
有人给了我目标
Someone told me not to give up.
也有人叫我不要放弃
Someone gave me a lucky charm.
还有人给了我护身符
Everyone is here for me
因为有这么多人支持着我
and that allows me to keep going.
我才能够向前迈进
And that day...
然后就是那一天
I was so happy.
我真的很开心
Like I finally achieved something.
有种终于达成的感觉
Achieve something...
达成…
And then,
然后啊
I thought I would be content since I achieved my dream.
我本来以为会因为现实梦想而满足
But there's an overflowing sense of joy.
但是这里有种满溢出来的心情
An overflowing sense of joy?
满溢出来的…心情
Yes.
是啊
It compels me to keep running.
我想继续奔跑下去
I then noticed
我这才发现
"GO WIN ARIMA KINEN" that I haven't become a strong
(有马纪念优胜) 我还没有成为像会长那样 强大又帅气的赛马娘
"SYMBOLI RUDOLF, ALL EYES ON VICTORY" I can't be the undefeated
(鲁道夫象征 专注于取胜之法) 我没能成为无败的三冠赛马娘
"SYMBOLI RUDOLF, ALL EYES ON VICTORY" I was forced to give up on it.
那是我不得不放弃的梦想
But it's still buried inside my heart.
但其实这个梦想还一直潜藏在我心底
And so,
所以…
Dream Trophy became my goal.
我才会以梦之杯联赛为目标
No matter what, I will become the Teio who surpasses the Emperor.
无论如何 我还是想要成为超越皇帝的帝王
That thought alone has been my motivation to persevere until now.
就是这样的想法 支持我一直努力到现在
Heh!
嘿咻
I won't ask what's bothering you now
我不会去问小北现在在烦恼些什么
because I know you're stronger than it.
不过 你一定没问题的
I'm sure
因为我相信
there's something irreplaceable inside your heart.
小北心里也一定有着 某种不会消失的东西
Teio...
帝皇…
Something irreplaceable...
某种不会消失的东西…
One, two, three, four.
一二三四…
Two, two, three, four.
二二三四…
-Two, two, three, four. -Start running now.
-接下来就是跑步 -二二三四…
Yes, madam.
是…
The dream
从最初开始
I have never given up on
就不曾放弃的东西
is Dad's performance.
是爸爸的表演
It's the soul-healing stage that makes everyone smile.
是那个让大家展露笑容 充满温馨气氛的地方
During Teio's race,
在帝皇比赛时
the audience was surrounded by hype and loud cheers.
观众席总是被火热的气氛所包围
It was loud, festive,
很热烈 也很热闹
and bright.
不停闪闪发光
So bright that it dazzled my eyes.
明亮到让人头晕目眩
I can still recall the scene vividly.
现在回想起来仍然历历在目
The clamor and the light, I remember them all.
那些光芒和声音 我全部都还记得
It still pains me to think
心里也会隐隐作痛
that I can never be
我也明白我做不到
a shining star like her.
无法像那样闪闪发光
But...
但是…
Come take a look. Cheap deals!
来看看 很便宜哦
Enjoy discounts during this special hour.
这个时间来买更划算哦
Don't miss out.
不要错过
We recommend bananas today.
现在最推荐的就是香蕉哦
I will put up the best performance.
我会将最棒的LIVE献给大家的
You can count on me.
包在我身上
Fresh bananas! Come take a look!
来看看 好吃的香蕉哦
Welcome.
欢迎光临
-Hi. -Yes?
-来哦 -你好
Hi, Kita.
小北 你好啊
It's cold today.
今天天气很凉呢
You're only wearing your tracksuit. Won't you be cold?
只穿运动服不会太冷吗
I'm jogging right now.
不是的 我现在在跑步
Is that so?
这样啊 你在跑步啊
You sure work so hard.
还真是努力
No... Not really.
不…不会
In Arima Kinen, I...
那个…在有马纪念时…
Oh, right. I have something for you, Kita.
对了 我有个好东西要给小北
Give me a second.
等我一下哦
Darling, where is the thing I put away again?
老婆 分好的那个放在哪里啊
What thing? Be specific.
只讲"那个"我哪知道是哪个啦
That thing! The thing for Kita.
就是"那个"啊 要给小北的"那个"
You always do this.
真是的 老公你总是这样
"ARIMA KINEN KITASAN BLACK PROMOTION"
(北部玄驹出赛有马纪念特卖) (洋葱1颗 1圆) 真是的 老公你总是这样
"1 ONION FOR 1 YEN" This thing, that thing, what thing is it?
(北部玄驹出赛有马纪念特卖) (洋葱1颗 1圆) 一下这个一下那个的 到底是哪个
That thing.
就是那个啦
"ARIMA KINEN KITASAN BLACK PROMOTION" Welcome. Come take a look.
(北部玄驹出赛有马纪念特卖) 欢迎光临 来看看哦
Everything's fresh here.
全都是新鲜货哦
Here you go.
给你
I imported some great carrots.
我进到了些不错的胡萝卜
You can have them.
拿去吧
Are you sure?
咦 这样好吗
Don't worry about it. Just take them.
没关系 你就带回去吧
Treat yourself tonight.
今晚好好填饱肚子
Kita, you should have these tomatoes too.
这样的话 小北 这些西红柿也拿去吧
They are very sweet.
很甜很好吃哦
I can't possibly accept them.
不…不好啦
I insist.
没关系啦
Let us pamper you once in a while.
偶尔也让我们慰劳你一下吧
After all, you're the star of this street.
毕竟你可是这个商店街的大明星呢
Star...
明星…
That's right.
哦 不错耶
Take this fish with you too.
那也把我们店的这条鱼带回去吧
Kita, this is our latest product. You like honey, don't you?
小北 这是我们店的新产品 你很喜欢蜂蜜对吧
Take this manju with you.
那么这个馒头也带回去吧
Have this meat too.
我们的肉也拿去吧
Do you want some apples?
我们家的苹果如何
Take some pastries with you.
我们家的糕点也拿去吧
I saved you the freshest fish.
给你 我选了条最新鲜的哦
She can't carry everything back.
喂 这么多她带不回去吧
She can use my basket.
那就用我家的笼子吧
I...
这…这些 我…
It's all we can do
虽然我们只能做到这样
to cheer for you, Kita.
但我们都想为你加油
Mhm.
是啊
You did so well in Arima Kinen.
之前有马纪念的比赛 实在是太棒了
I shouted so much that my throat hurt.
比完才发现我都嗓子喊哑了
It is very memorable.
真的很棒呢
Especially the last sprint before the finishing line.
尤其是终点前的那场大激战
It brings me to tears whenever I think about it.
光是想起来 眼泪就快掉下来了呢
That soul-healing stage that makes everyone smile.
展露笑容 充满温馨气氛的地方
It's loud, festive,
总是被火热的气氛所包围
and bright.
很热烈 很热闹 不停闪闪发光
So bright that it dazzles my eyes.
明亮到让人头晕目眩的地方
My first dream...
我最初的…梦想
I buried it away in my heart.
明明将这样的情感藏在了心底…
I gave up on it. But...
明明都已经放弃了…
Kita.
小北…
Are you hurt or something?
怎么了 是身体哪里不舒服吗
No, not at all.
不是的 不是这样的…
I... I...
只是那个…那个…
Thank you so much.
各位 谢谢你们
Wait.
等一下
Kita.
小北
Where did Kita go?
小北到底跑到哪里去了
I'm back.
我回来了
Kita, you're back.
小北你回来啦
What's with the basket?
那篮东西是怎么回事
Bye.
我出门了
"SYMBOLI RUDOLF, ALL EYES ON VICTORY" I feel good.
(鲁道夫象征 专注于取胜之法) 清清爽爽…
All the best, Kita.
加油哦 小北
I like to see a smile on everyone's face.
我最喜欢大家的笑容
I want to be at a place where everyone is enjoying themselves, like a festival.
最喜欢有着众多笑容 像是祭典一般的地方
I can't have enough
那一天 帝皇所创造的光景
of the moment Teio created.
我果然还是非常喜欢
I cannot be like Teio.
我无法成为帝皇
I cannot shine like her.
我无法闪闪发光
I am not a prodigy.
我也无法成为天才
So I gave up on my dream.
所以我放弃了梦想
But this is different from my true calling.
这一切跟我的理想完全不同
The truth will never change.
今后肯定也是这样
I cannot become a prodigy.
我无法成为天才
I cannot become a star.
也无法成为明星
I know that. I'm aware of that.
我明白 我通通都明白
But I don't want to give up.
不过 我还是不想放弃
I want to chase after my dream.
我想要再度去追求
I want to find my dream again.
去把我的梦想追回来
I want to create the moment.
我想要创造出那样的光景
I want it.
我要创造出来